

Md. Mahmudul Islam

CONTACT

Address:

62/C, Green Road, Panthapath, Tejgaon, Dhaka, Bangladesh.

Permanent Address: Banshopata, Talora, Dupchanchia, Bogura, Bangladesh

Phone:

+8801521404361

Email:

mahmudul7959@gmail.com

PROFILE

Portfolio:

https://mahmud.hexcursion.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahmudul7959/

Github:

https://github.com/Mahmud-CSE16

StopStalk:

https://www.stopstalk.com/user/profile/Mahmud_CSE16



Summary

I'm a **Full Stack Developer** and fully passionate to develop something new with the latest technology. I'm well-versed in numerous programming languages. I have experience developing 20+ mobile apps and 5+ websites as well as working as team member and lead the team.



Education

I graduated(2017 - 2022) in **Computer Science and Engineering** from Khulna University of Engineering & Technology.



Skill highlights



- Flutter (Android, iOS and Web)
 - · Getx, Provider & MVVM
 - · Customize all kind of widgets as required
 - · CustomPaint, Animation
- 6+ live applications



Android Studio

- Jetpack Architecture, MVVM
- · Custom UI design, Animation
- Rest APIs(Retrofit)
- 7+ live applications



Django

- All kind of back-end task
- Database (MySQL and Postgres)
- · GUI for machine learning
- Rest APIs (Django Rest Framework)
- 3+ applications



Reactis

- Hooks, Context, Reducer, Redux
- · Custom UI design, Animation
- Rest APIs (Axios)
- 5+ applications

More Skills













Xcode

Firebase

Map

Nodeis

Nextjs

ML











AWS

Vimeo

Xd

Figma

Git



Experiences



Prottoy visual learning platform

Chief Technical Officer

Aug-2020 - Present

- Developed an Edtech platform for BD students. Where students can take pre-recorded & online classes, exams as well as they can ask questions through the app.
- Taking whole responsibilities for technical resources
- Visit : [Android] [Web]



Ongrocery (Zatiq)

Software Engineer

May-2021 - Present

- Ongrocery is a shopping app to sell grocery products from around the world
- · My responsibility is to develop and improve features in Ongrocery App
- Built mobile based admin panel and Invoice generator.
- Visit : [Android] [iOS] [Web]



Software Engineer

Feb-2020 - Present

- During this time period, I have been working on 7 separate projects. There, I have built and currently maintain 12+ Apps. Some of them are mentioned here.

Hidmona - Money Transfer

- International money transfer application among countries worldwide
- Visit: [Android] [iOS] [Web]

GetBetal - Money Transfer

- International money transfer application among countries worldwide
- Visit: [Android] [iOS] [Web]

MyCash – Amtel Ltd

- MyCash is modern Mobile based Money Transfer system with Amtel company
- Visit: [Subscriber] [Agent] [Merchent] [Web]

Small World Money

- SW Money is Mobile based Money Transfer system in Ivory Coast
- Visit: [Client] [Agent]



BCS Confidence

Routine Management System (contract)

Jan-2022 – Jun-2022

- Automate whole routine management across all branches.
- Admin, branch manager and teacher can add, edit and see the routine base on user role.



EasyTrax Ltd

Software Developer (contract)

May-2020 – May-2021

- Developing complex UI/UX for Easytrax GPS Tracking App.
- Developed numerous email templates for emailing to clients with a clean interface.
- Visit: [Android] [iOS] [Web]



Extra-Curricular Activities



Bit2Bite (Software Research & Development community of KUET)

Vice President

Sep-2020 – March-2022

- Through **Bit2Bite** we organize workshops on software research and development where our seniors are training us(junior).
- I conducted 3 workshops as a trainer.



HACK (Hardware Acceleration Club of KUET)

Organizing Secretary

March-2020 - March-2022

- Through **HACK** we organize workshops on Hardware and IOT where our seniors are training us(junior).
- I conducted 5 workshops as a trainer.